encyclopedia-titanica.org 2011-11-21

# Encyclopedia Titanica : Privacy

This page explains what information might be gathered about you when you visit encyclopedia-titanica.org. 

**What is collected and stored:** ET collects data volunteered by users by signing up to receive newsletters or creating a message board profile. Certain data is also created automatically when you interact with the site. 

**What is done with the information:** ET uses the personal information you provide voluntarily to send information and services that you have requested. e.g. When you subscribe to the mailing list or message board you must provide your email address. 

**Security:** ET will take all reasonable steps to prevent persoanl data being extracted by third parties. All personal data is held in secure parts of the site although some (e.g. message board profiles) are publically accessible. If you are a message board member you can restrict access to your e-mail address by setting your profile to hide the address. You should never remove the address as it is needed for administrative purposes and if you wish to receive messages in your in-box. We will never sell or rent your email address or personal data to any third party and would only disclose personal information if requred to by UK law. 

**Server Logs:** ET may analyze visitors' use of the site by tracking information such as pageviews, traffic flow, search terms, and click through. We use this information to improve the site. We reserve the right to make this anonymous traffic and demographic information available in aggregate form but do not share any information can identify an individual user.   
ET may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Cookies:** A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer's hard drive through your web browser when you visit ET. Cookies enable the system to recognize your computer, so that you can receive a personalized response. This is largely of use on the message board. You can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies or to block cookies. If you block cookies, you may not be able to use certain site features or functions. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

* Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.  
* Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet.  
* Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy. 

**External Links and Services:** This site contains links to other sites. ET is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Web Sites. 

**Opting Out:** You may opt out of mailing lists by clicking unsubscribe link from our newsletter. You may delete your ET account at any time from your profile manager.

* * *

_Revision Date 14 February 2002_
